dzogchen.net 2018-10-05

# Privacy Policy

                                             Privacy Policy
Table of content
1 Introduc+on
 ...............................................................................................................................................................2
2 Data Protec+on Oﬃcer .......................................................................................................................3
3 How we collect and use (process) your personal informa+on close ...................................................3
    3.1 Personal informa+on you give to us: ............................................................................................3
        3.1.1 Prior to your IDC Membership.............................................................................................. 3
        3.1.2 IDC Membership .................................................................................................................... 4
        3.1.3 Live events and webcast events, trainings .............................................................................4
        3.1.4 Cer+ﬁca+on ...........................................................................................................................5
        3.1.5 Content .................................................................................................................................. 5
        3.1.6 Your correspondence with the IDC ........................................................................................5
        3.1.7 Purposes for processing your data ........................................................................................6
    3.2 What happens if you don’t give us your data ...............................................................................6
4 Use of the dzogchen.net website ........................................................................................................6
5 Cookies and web beacons ...................................................................................................................7
6 When and how we share informa+on with others close.....................................................................8
7 Personal data transfers ........................................................................................................................9
8 Data subject rights close .....................................................................................................................9
9 Security of your informa+on .............................................................................................................10
10 Data storage and reten+on .............................................................................................................10
11 Changes and updates to the Privacy No+ce ....................................................................................11
12 Ques+ons, concerns or complaints ................................................................................................11
                                                                                                                                                                1

1 Introduc1on
The Interna+onal Dzogchen Community with seat at Merigar, Arcidosso, (GR), Italy (“IDC”) is an
interna+onal non-for-proﬁt organiza+on that brings together people who are commiced to study
and prac+ce the Dzogchen A+ Teaching under the guidance of a master possessing authen+c
knowledge of the state of Dzogchen. It supports the evolu+on of individuals and promotes social
aims.
We understand that you are aware of and care about your own personal privacy interests, and we
take that seriously. This Privacy No+ce describes the IDC’s policies and prac+ces regarding its
collec+on and use of your personal data, and sets forth your privacy rights in compliance with the
Regula+on (EU) 2016/679 Of The European Parliament and of the Council of 27 April 2016 on the
protec+on of natural persons with regard to the processing of personal data and on the free
movement of such data, and repealing Direc+ve 95/46/EC (General Data Protec+on Regula+on)
(“GDPR”). We recognize that informa+on privacy is an ongoing responsibility, and so we will from
+me to +me update this Privacy No+ce as we undertake new personal data prac+ces or adopt new
privacy policies.
We do not knowingly acempt to solicit or receive informa+on from children. To become a member
of IDC (“IDC member”) one needs to reach the age of 18 years or older.
As IDC is also composed of Gars (the main seats of IDC in a speciﬁc geographical area) and Lings (the
local seats/centers within a single country), described below in these cases, your personal data
controllers are the IDC and the respec+ve Gar that your Ling is aﬃliated to. In the posi+on of joint
controllers it is hereinafer referred to as “we”.
Under the joint controllership agreement pursuant to Ar+cle 26 GDPR, s+pulated by the
aforemen+oned joint controllers, the controller that determines the purposes of the processing and
guarantees the security measures under Ar+cle 32 of the GDPR is the IDC; with regards to the
guarantee of the rights of the data, the joint controller in charge of responding to requests for
informa+on and the exercise of the rights under Ar+cle 13 and seq. GDPR is the IDC; provided that
you can exercise your rights under the GDPR before each and every joint controller.
                                                                                                     2

2 Data Protec1on Oﬃcer
The IDC is headquartered in Arcidosso in Italy. The IDC has appointed an internal data protec+on
oﬃcer for you to contact if you have any ques+ons or concerns about the IDC’s personal data policies
or prac+ces. The IDC’s data protec+on oﬃcer’s name and contact informa+on are as follows:
Vera Taihucu
dpo@dzogchen.net
3 How we collect and use (process) your personal informa1on close
3.1 Personal informa1on you give to us:
3.1.1 Prior to your IDC Membership
The process of acquiring an IDC membership is governed by the Membership Regula+ons which you
may ﬁnd at hcp://dzogchencommunity.org/documents/.
A person who is interested to eventually become an IDC member should apply for a Welcome Card.
Should you be granted a Welcome Card, we process the following informa+on about you:
        •        First name, last name, original family name, birth date;
        •        preferred local Community;
        •        street address, city, postal code, state/ province, country of residence
        •        ID number;
        •        telephone number, email address, county of birth and ci+zenship,
        •        Welcome Card fee payments;
Welcome Card holder informa+on is registered in the Membership Database, maintained in the
Membership Management System (“MMS”) and available through the IDC Member Directory to
other IDC members using the Dzogchen.net website. Welcome Card holders are invited to opt-in to
having their informa+on shared in the Member Directory.
                                                                                                   3

3.1.2 IDC Membership
When you become an IDC member, we collect the following informa+on about you:
•        ﬁrst name, last name, original family name, birth date;
•        preferred local Community;
•        street address, city, postal code, state/ province, country of residence
•        ID number;
•        telephone number, email address, county of birth and ci+zenship,
•        membership fee payments;
•        membership dura+on and membership type;
•        account of your trainings, cer+ﬁca+ons, exams and other events passed;
•        username and password to your proﬁle at www.dzogchencommunity.net (“Proﬁle”).
The personal data are not disclosed outside IDC without the consent of the data subjects.
We ask IDC members to voluntarily provide addi+onal informa+on in their Proﬁle held at
www.dzogchen.net. IDC members may edit their Proﬁle at any +me to change, add, or remove
personal informa+on.
The IDC makes IDC member informa+on available through the IDC Member Directory to other IDC
members using the Dzogchen.net website. Members are invited to opt-in to having their informa+on
shared in the Member Directory maintained in the MMS.
If you are an IDC member, we process your personal informa+on for the purposes of your
membership administra+on, to deliver IDC member beneﬁts to you, and to inform you of IDC-related
events, content, and other beneﬁts or opportuni+es associated with your IDC membership.
3.1.3 Live events and webcast events, trainings
The IDC hosts many events throughout the year. These include in-person teaching retreats like the
teaching retreats given by Chögyal Namkhai Norbu, for example, as well as live web events
(collec+vely “webcasts”).
If you register for one of our webcasts and you are an IDC member, we might access the informa+on
in your IDC member account to provide you with informa+on and services associated with the event.
If you par+cipate in IDC training, like Vajra Dance, Yantra Yoga, San+ Maha Sangha or Khaita you may
sign up directly through the IDC in which case we collect your name and contact informa+on directly
from you. You may, alterna+vely, sign up for training – or be signed up for training. Unless it is stated
as an “open course” you must be an IDC member to par+cipate in one of more of the following
trainings men+oned here above.
If you are not an IDC member and you register for one of our events or trainings, we will collect your
name and contact informa+on for the purposes of the event or training administra+on, and we will
delete it afer the event, if there is no other legal ground for such processing..
                                                                                                         4

3.1.4 Cer1ﬁca1on
When you sign up to take one of the IDC’s cer+ﬁca+on exams, we will collect your name and contact
informa+on. We will also collect and store informa+on you provide to us about your need for special
accommoda+ons. This informa+on may be shared with our IDC training administrator service. The
IDC will collect your exam results and, in conjunc+on with maintaining your cer+ﬁca+on(s), your
record of par+cipa+on in con+nuing privacy educa+on. Only authorized IDC members within the IDC
have access to your cer+ﬁca+ons and personal informa+on in regards with this speciﬁc training/
cer+ﬁca+on.
3.1.5 Content
The IDC websites oﬀer a great deal of content for IDC members, but for a broad public too.
You may wish to subscribe to the IDC’s informa+on mailings without becoming an IDC member. For
example, people might sign up to receive the IDC mailings even though they are not IDC members.
Should you grant us your explicit consent by +cking the box at the consent form on our websites or in
a paper form; we will process your personal data also for the following purposes:
         • communica+on with you regarding our ac+vi+es, namely trainings, webcasts,
         presenta+ons, mee+ngs and other ac+vi+es and applica+ons run by us our by our partners,
         and other informa+on related to our ac+vi+es and goals (usually via e-mail “newslecer”).
         This communica+on can be carried out in an electronic or paper mail form, via phone, in
         person or through other distance means;
         • use of the history of your acendance to our events, including the informa+on on your
         poten+al IDC membership in order to send you the newslecers the most relevant to you
Gran+ng of such consent is free and you are not obliged to grant it based on any legal prescrip+on.
You may withdraw your consent at any +me, the lawfulness of your personal data processing prior to
such withdrawal being untouched.
Moreover, you may reject any further mailings at any +me, without any impact on our rela+onship.
In order to reject any further mailing, you can follow the link placed in the sent newslecer or to send
an e-mail to dpo@dzogchen.net
If you have any diﬃcul+es managing your email or other communica+on preferences with the IDC,
please contact us at dpo@dzogchen.net.
3.1.6 Your correspondence with the IDC
If you correspond with us by e-mail, the postal service, or other form of communica+on, we may
retain such correspondence and the informa+on contained in it and use it to respond to your
inquiry;; or to keep a record of your complaint, accommoda+on request, and the like, for the period
necessary to solve your request. As always, if you wish to have the IDC “erase” your personal
                                                                                                      5

informa+on or otherwise refrain from communica+ng with you, please contact us at
dpo@dzogchen.net.
Note: if you ask the IDC not to contact you by e-mail at a certain e-mail address, the IDC will retain a
copy of that e-mail address on its “master do not send” list in order to comply with your no-contact
request.
3.1.7 Purposes for processing your data
As explained above, the IDC processes your data to provide you with the services you have requested
from us, including Welcome Card holder or an IDC membership services, events and other content,
cer+ﬁca+on, and training.
We use this informa+on to communicate with you about other services the IDC oﬀers that may assist
you in your prac+ce par+cipa+on, in case we have your consent for this purpose.
3.2 What happens if you don’t give us your data
You can enjoy many of the IDC’s services without giving us your personal data. Much of the
informa+on on our website is available even to those who are not IDC members. If you are an IDC
member, you can enter only the minimal amount of informa+on (name and contact informa+on) to
your Proﬁle if you wish, and you can edit your Proﬁle at any +me and minimize the data included.
Some personal informa+on is necessary so that the IDC can supply you with the services you have
purchased or requested (e.g. trainings, events registra+on etc.), and to authen+cate you so that we
know it is you and not someone else. You may manage your IDC subscrip+ons and you may opt-out
of receiving IDC communica+on at any +me.
4 Use of the dzogchen.net website
As is true of most other websites, the IDC’s website collects certain informa+on automa+cally and
stores it in log ﬁles. The informa+on may include internet protocol (IP) addresses, the region or
general loca+on where your computer or device is accessing the internet, browser type, opera+ng
system and other usage informa+on about the use of the IDC’s website, including a history of the
pages you view. We use this informa+on to help us design our site to becer suit our users’ needs. We
may also use your IP address to help diagnose problems with our server and to administer our
website, analyze trends, track visitor movements, and gather broad demographic informa+on that
assists us in iden+fying visitor preferences. The IDC’s website also uses cookies and web beacons. It
does not track users when they cross to third party websites, does not provide targeted adver+sing
to them, and therefore does not respond to Do Not Track (DNT) signals.
                                                                                                         6

5 Cookies and web beacons
Cookies are pieces of data that a Web site transfers to a user's hard drive for record-keeping
purposes. Web beacons are transparent pixel images that are used in collec+ng informa+on about
website usage, e-mail response and tracking.
The website uses cookies and web beacons to provide enhanced func+onality on the website (e.g.,
user ID and password prompts or event registra+on) and aggregate traﬃc data (e.g., what pages are
the most popular). These cookies may be delivered in a ﬁrst-party or third-party context. The IDC
may also use cookies and web beacons in associa+on with e-mails delivered by the IDC. Our website
also captures limited informa+on (user-agent, HTTP referrer, last URL requested by the user, client-
side and server-side clickstream) about visits to our website; we may use this informa+on to analyze
general traﬃc pacerns and to perform rou+ne system maintenance. You have many choices with
regards to the management of cookies on your computer. All major browsers allow you to block or
delete cookies from your system. To learn more about your ability to manage cookies and web
beacons, please consult the privacy features in your browser.
This website uses Google Analy+cs, a web analy+cs service provided by Google, Inc. ("Google") to
track how ofen people gain access to or read our content. We use this informa+on in the aggregate
to understand what content our members ﬁnd useful or interes+ng, so we can produce the most
valuable content to meet your needs. Google Analy+cs uses "cookies", which are text ﬁles placed on
your computer, to help the website analyze how users use the site. The informa+on generated by the
cookie about your use of the website (including your IP address) will be transmiced to and stored by
Google on servers in the Europe. Google will use this informa+on for the purposes of evalua+ng your
use of the website, compiling reports on website ac+vity for website operators and providing other
services rela+ng to website ac+vity and internet usage. Google may also transfer this informa+on to
third par+es where required to do so by law, or where such third par+es process the informa+on on
Google's behalf. Google will not associate your IP address with any other data held by Google. You
may refuse the use of cookies by selec+ng the appropriate seungs on your browser, however please
note that if you do this you might not be able to use the full func+onality of this website. By using
the IDC website, you consent to the processing of data about you by Google in the manner and for
the purposes set out above.
The IDC also might use a communica+on database management program that deploys a cookie when
a user interacts with a direct communica+on, such as an e-mail .This cookie collects personal
informa+on such as your name, which pages you visit on the IDC website, your history arriving at the
IDC website, your purchases from the IDC and the like. We use this informa+on to evaluate the
eﬀec+veness of our communica+ons. You may set your browser to block these cookies.
                                                                                                      7

We also, from +me to +me, conduct surveys that we use to improve our services to our IDC
members. We do not track individuals but look at informa+on in the aggregate only. Par+cipa+on in
surveys is voluntary.
6 When and how we share informa1on with others close
Informa+on about your Proﬁle is maintained in associa+on with your membership or Proﬁle. The
personal informa+on the IDC collects from you is stored in one or more databases hosted by a
hos+ngprovider located in Europe. This party does not use or have access to your personal
informa+on for any purpose other than cloud storage and retrieval and are bound to stringent
technical and organiza+onal safety measure, ensuring the integrity and conﬁden+ality of your
personal data.
We do not otherwise reveal your personal data to third-par+es for their independent use, unless: (1)
you request or authorize it with your speciﬁc consent; (2) it’s in connec+on with IDC-hosted and IDC
co-sponsored events you registered to, and only for the purposes of this event organiza+on, provided
that the third party shall not be authorized to use the data for their own purposes afer the
respec+ve event; (3) the informa+on is provided to comply with the law (for example, to comply with
a search warrant, subpoena or court order), enforce an agreement we have with you, or to protect
our rights, property or safety, or the rights, property or safety of our employees or others; (4) the
informa+on might be provided to Shang Shung Ins+tute ( SSI) who perform some educa+onal and
book publishing func+ons on our behalf and acts as the data processor based on speciﬁc wricen data
processing agreement; (5) to address emergencies or unexpected consequences with your consent;
or (6) to address disputes, claims, or to persons demonstra+ng legal authority to act on your behalf;
and (7) through the IDC Member Directory should you become a Welcome Card holder or an IDC
member.
In all above described cases we share your data only to the extent necessary for the respec+ve
purposes and ensuring that there is a valid legal ground for such transfer to the respec+ve recipient.
We may also gather anonymized and aggregated data about our members and website visitors and
disclose the results of such aggregated (but not personally iden+ﬁable) informa+on to our partners,
like non-aﬃliated Lings, meaning Lings who aren’t legally aligned or are in the process geung aligned
with IDC. List of ( not yet or non-) aﬃliated Lings are given upon request by the DPO.
The IDC website might use interfaces with social media sites such as Facebook. If you choose to "like"
or share informa+on from the IDC website through these services, you should review the privacy
policy of that service. If you are a member of a social media site, the interfaces may allow the social
media site to connect your site visit to your personal data.
                                                                                                        8

7 Personal data transfers
Transferring personal data from the EU to the US
The IDC has its headquarters in Arcidosso, Italy. Informa+on we collect from you will be processed in
Italy. The United States has not sought nor received a ﬁnding of “adequacy” decision from the
European Commission under Ar+cle 45 of the GDPR.
The IDC applies suitable safeguards to protect the privacy and security of your personal data and to
use it only consistent with your rela+onship with the IDC and the prac+ces described in this Privacy
No+ce.
The IDC also minimizes the risk to your rights and freedoms by not collec+ng or storing speciﬁc
categories of data about you, apart from your religious beliefs which are processed inevitably with
the nature of IDC.
8 Data subject rights close
The GDPR and other countries’ privacy laws provide certain rights for data subjects. A good
explana+on of them (in English) is available on the website of the United Kingdom’s Informa+on
Commissioner’s Oﬃce.
This Privacy No+ce is intended to provide you with informa+on about what personal data the IDC
collects about you and how it is used. If you have any ques+ons, please contact us at
dpo@dzogchen.net.
If you wish to conﬁrm that the IDC is processing your personal data, or to have access to the personal
data the IDC may have about you, please contact us at dpo@dzogchen.net.
You may also request informa+on about: the purpose of the processing; the categories of personal
data concerned; who else outside the IDC might have received the data from the IDC; what the
source of the informa+on was (if you didn’t provide it directly to the IDC); and how long it will be
stored. You have a right to correct (rec+fy) the record of your personal data maintained by the IDC if
it is inaccurate. You may request that the IDC erase that data or cease processing it, subject to certain
excep+ons. You may also request that the IDC cease using your data for direct communica+on
purposes. You have a right to lodge a complaint with the appropriate data protec+on authority if you
have concerns about how the IDC processes your personal data. You have also the right to receive
your personal data you provided to us, in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable
format and have the right to transmit those data to another controller without hindrance our side,
                                                                                                        9

where the processing is based on consent or on a contract and the processing is carried out by
automated means.
Access to your personal data will be provided at no cost upon request made to the IDC at
dpo@dzogchen.net. If access cannot be provided within a reasonable +me frame, the IDC will
provide you with a date when the informa+on will be provided, that period may be extended by two
further months where necessary, taking into account the complexity and number of the requests. If
for some reason access is denied, the IDC will provide an explana+on as to why access has been
denied.
9 Security of your informa1on
To help protect the privacy of data and personally iden+ﬁable informa+on you transmit through use
of this website, we maintain physical, technical and administra+ve safeguards. We update and test
our security technology on an ongoing basis. We restrict access to your personal data to those IDC
members who need to know that informa+on to provide beneﬁts or services to you. In addi+on, we
train our selected IDC members about the importance of conﬁden+ality and maintaining the privacy
and security of your informa+on. We commit to taking appropriate disciplinary measures to enforce
our IDC members' privacy responsibili+es.
10 Data storage and reten1on
Your personal data is stored by the IDC on servers, located in Europe.
The IDC retains data for the dura+on of the IDC member’s membership with the IDC, or Welcome
Card validity.
Any informa+on related to data subjects not becoming IDC members or Welcome Card holders,
regarding the events or trainings acended, are not processed later than necessary for provision of
such service to the respec+ve data subject.
Any informa+on we process based on your explicit consent will be erased afer your consent is
withdrawn.
For more informa+on on where and how long your personal data is stored, and for more informa+on
on your rights of erasure and portability, please contact the IDC’s data protec+on oﬃcer at
dpo@dzogchen.net.
                                                                                                   10

11 Changes and updates to the Privacy No1ce
By using this website, you agree to the terms and condi+ons contained in this Privacy No+ce and/or
any other agreement that we might have with you. If you do not agree to any of these terms and
condi+ons, you should not use this website or any IDC beneﬁts or services. You agree that any
dispute over privacy or the terms contained in this Privacy No+ce, or any other agreement we have
with you, will be governed by the laws of the EU. You also agree to arbitrate such disputes in EU, and
to abide by any limita+on on damages contained in any agreement we may have with you.
As our organiza+on, membership and beneﬁts change from +me to +me, this Privacy No+ce is
expected to change as well. We reserve the right to amend the Privacy No+ce at any +me, for any
reason, without no+ce to you, other than the pos+ng of the amended Privacy No+ce at this website.
We may e-mail periodic reminders of our no+ces and terms and condi+ons and will e-mail IDC
members of material changes thereto, but you should check our website frequently to see the
current Privacy No+ce that is in eﬀect and any changes that may have been made to it. The
provisions contained herein supersede all previous no+ces or statements regarding our privacy
prac+ces and the terms and condi+ons that govern the use of this website.
12 Ques1ons, concerns or complaints
Please contact the IDC’s data protec+on oﬃcer: dpo@dzogchen.net
                                                                                                     11
